{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A computerized self-diagnostic for a ROM test uses:", "opta": "the check-sum method", "optb": "a ROM listing", "optc": "ROM comparisons", "optd": "a checkerboard test", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many storage locations are available when a memory device has twelve address lines?", "opta": "144", "optb": "512", "optc": "2048", "optd": "4096", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following memories uses a MOSFET and a capacitor as its memory cell?", "opta": "SRAM", "optb": "DRAM", "optc": "ROM", "optd": "DROM", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes nonvolatile memory?", "opta": "memory that retains stored information when electrical power is removed", "optb": "memory that loses stored information when electrical power is removed", "optc": "magnetic memory", "optd": "nonmagnetic memory", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The access time (tacc) of a memory IC is governed by the IC's:", "opta": "internal address buffer", "optb": "internal address decoder", "optc": "volatility", "optd": "internal address decoder and volatility", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the best description of read-only memory (ROM).", "opta": "nonvolatile, used to store information that changes during system operation", "optb": "nonvolatile, used to store information that does not change during system operation", "optc": "volatile, used to store information that changes during system operation", "optd": "volatile, used to store information that does not change during system operation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Advantage(s) of an EEPROM over an EPROM is (are):", "opta": "the EPROM can be erased with ultraviolet light in much less time than an EEPROM", "optb": "the EEPROM can be erased and reprogrammed without removal from the circuit", "optc": "the EEPROM has the ability to erase and reprogram individual words", "optd": "the EEPROM can erase and reprogram individual words without removal from the circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following RAM timing parameters determine(s) its operating speed?", "opta": "tacc", "optb": "taa and tacs", "optc": "t1 and t3", "optd": "trc and twc", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Memory that loses its contents when power is lost is:", "opta": "nonvolatile", "optb": "volatile", "optc": "random", "optd": "static", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the best description of the fusible-link PROM.", "opta": "user programmable, one-time programmable", "optb": "manufacturer programmable, one-time programmable", "optc": "user programmable, reprogrammable", "optd": "manufacturer programmable, reprogrammable", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nonvolatile type of memory that can be programmed and erased in sectors, rather than one byte at a time is:", "opta": "flash memory", "optb": "EPROM", "optc": "EEPROM", "optd": "MPROM", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes static memory devices?", "opta": "memory devices that are magnetic in nature and do not require constant refreshing", "optb": "semiconductor memory devices in which stored data is retained as long as power is applied", "optc": "memory devices that are magnetic in nature and require constant refreshing", "optd": "semiconductor memory devices in which stored data will not be retained with the power applied unless constantly refreshed", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the principal advantage of using address multiplexing with DRAM memory?", "opta": "reduced memory access time", "optb": "reduced requirement for constant refreshing of the memory contents", "optc": "reduced pin count and decrease in package size", "optd": "no requirement for a chip-select input line, thereby reducing the pin count", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}